<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?><Researcher><Total_num_cit_autor>71</Total_num_cit_autor><Total_cit_ano><Ano><Id>2010</Id><Num>2</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2011</Id><Num>5</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2012</Id><Num>10</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2013</Id><Num>17</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2016</Id><Num>1</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2014</Id><Num>15</Num></Ano><Ano><Id>2015</Id><Num>21</Num></Ano></Total_cit_ano><Publications><Publication><Title>Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems</Title><Authors>Javier Cámara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2015/5/4</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—An increasingly important requirement for certain classes of software-intensive systems is the ability to self-adapt their structure and behavior at run-time when reacting to changes that may occur to the system, its environment, or its goals. A major challenge related to self-adaptive software systems is the ability to provide assurances of their resilience when facing changes. Since in these systems, the components that act as controllers of a target system incorporate highly complex software, there is the need to ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>1</Quantity><Citation><Title>Software Resilience and the Effectiveness of Software Mitigation in Microcontrollers.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Characterizing the performance of web service frameworks under security attacks</Title><Authors>Rui André Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2015/4/13</Publication_date><Description>Abstract Web Services are a platform-independent technology that enables business processes to be accessible worldwide. In this context, web service frameworks play a key role as intermediate layers, offering support for interoperability and communication between providers and consumers. Due to their relevance in the overall infrastructure, frameworks are a frequent target of attacks trying to impact the performance of the provided services. This paper proposes an experimental approach for assessing the performance of web ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>1</Quantity><Citation><Title>Detection of Lightweight Directory Access Protocol Query Injection Attacks in Web Applications.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Understanding Interoperability Issues of Web Service Frameworks</Title><Authors>Ivano Alessandro Elia, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2014/6/23</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Web Services are a set of technologies designed to support the invocation of remote services by client applications, with the key goal of providing interoperable application-to-application interaction while supporting vendor and platform independence. The goal of this work is to study the real level of interoperability provided by these technologies through a massive experimental campaign involving a wide set of very popular frameworks for web services, implemented using seven different programming languages. ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>3</Quantity><Citation><Title>A Practical Approach Towards Automatic Testing of Web Services Interoperability.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>ITWS: An Extensible Tool for Interoperability Testing of Web Services.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A Field Perspective on the Interoperability of Web Services.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Testing the robustness of controllers for self-adaptive systems</Title><Authors>Javier Cámara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2014/1/23</Publication_date><Description>Abstract Self-adaptive systems are software-intensive systems endowed with the ability to respond to a variety of changes that may occur in their environment, goals, or the system itself by adapting their structure and behaviour at run-time in an autonomous way. Controllers are complex components incorporated in self-adaptive systems, which are crucial to their function since they are in charge of adapting the target system by executing actions through effectors, based on information monitored by probes. However, although ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>6</Quantity><Citation><Title>Towards a framework for testing and simulating self adaptive systems.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A Testing Scheme for Self-Adaptive Software Systems with Architectural Runtime Models.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Design Patterns for Self Adaptive Systems Engineering.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Automated generation of adaptive test plans for self-adaptive systems.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A Formal Approach for Designing Distributed Self-Adaptive Systems.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Perpetual assurances in self-adaptive systems.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>A technique for deploying robust web services</Title><Authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</Authors><Publication_date>2014/1</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Developing robust web services is a difficult task. Field studies show that a large number of web services are deployed with robustness problems (ie, presenting unexpected behaviors in the presence of invalid inputs). Although several techniques for the identification of robustness problems have been proposed in the past, there is no practical approach to automatically fix those problems. This paper proposes a mechanism that automatically fixes robustness problems in web services. The approach consists of using ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>6</Quantity><Citation><Title>Assessing Dependability with Software Fault Injection: A Survey.</Title><Date>2016</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>ENDORSE THE TRUSTFUL QoS TO CRAFT MASHUP/BUSINESS ORIENTED WEB SERVICES AND RECTIFY MALICIOUS ATTACKS.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Security slicing for auditing XML, XPath, and SQL injection vulnerabilities.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Validation Techniques for Fault Emulation of SRAM-based FPGAs.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Towards Patching Memory Leak Bugs in Off-The-Shelf Software.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>An empirical study of injected versus actual interface errors.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Towards evaluating the impact of data quality on service applications</Title><Authors>Naghmeh Ivaki, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2013/6/24</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Service applications frequently make use of a relational database to store and retrieve data and rely on the correctness of this data to deliver service to clients. Despite this, relational databases do not provide support for complex data integrity restrictions, which have to be controlled by the application. As such, bugs present in service applications can easily lead to the storage of incorrect data that, at random instants can cause applications to fail and stop delivering service, which can severely impact clients, other applications, and ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>1</Quantity><Citation><Title>A Survey on Data Quality: Classifying Poor Data.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Robustness evaluation of controllers in self-adaptive software systems</Title><Authors>Javier Camara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Renato Ventura, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2013/4/1</Publication_date><Description>Abstract An increasingly important requirement for softwareintensive systems is the ability to self-manage by adapting their structure and behavior at run-time in an autonomous way as a response to a variety of changes that may occur to the system, its environment, or its goals. In particular, self-adaptive (or autonomic) systems incorporate complex software components that act as controllers of a target system by executing actions through effectors, based on information monitored by probes. However, although these controllers are ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>6</Quantity><Citation><Title>Software Frameworks for SDR.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Robustness evaluation of the rainbow framework for self-adaptation.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Empirical resilience evaluation of an architecture-based self-adaptive software system.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Testing the robustness of controllers for self-adaptive systems.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>HLA Middleware Robustness and Scalability Evaluation in the Context of Satellite Simulators.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>WSFAggressor: an extensible web service framework attacking tool</Title><Authors>Rui André Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2012/12/6</Publication_date><Description>Abstract This paper presents a tool for testing the security of web service frameworks. The tool implements a large set of attack types, defined based on previous security research studies, existing testing tools, and field experience. The motivation is that developers frequently build web services based on the assumption that the underlying frameworks are secure, which is not always the case. Despite the evident need for security in the platforms that support services, existing security testing tools are very limited. In practice, most tools ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>4</Quantity><Citation><Title>Assessing the security of web service frameworks against Denial of Service attacks.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Known XML Vulnerabilities Are Still a Threat to Popular Parsers and Open Source Systems.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Characterizing the performance of web service frameworks under security attacks.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Entwurf einer Methodik zum Testen der Sicherheit von Web-Service-basierten Systemen.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>A robustness testing approach for SOAP Web services</Title><Authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</Authors><Publication_date>2012/9/1</Publication_date><Description>Abstract The use of Web services in enterprise applications is quickly increasing. In a Web services environment, providers supply a set of services for consumers. However, although Web services are being used in business-critical environments, there are no practical means to test or compare their robustness to invalid and malicious inputs. In fact, client applications are typically developed with the assumption that the services being used are robust, which is not always the case. Robustness failures in such environments are particularly dangerous ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>3</Quantity><Citation><Title>Bringing Test-Driven Development to web service choreographies.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Proposed design and implementation for RESTful web server.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Towards evaluating the impact of data quality on service applications.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Experimental evaluation of web service frameworks in the presence of security attacks</Title><Authors>Rui Andre Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2012/6/24</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Web services are increasingly being used to provide critical operations in business-to-business and safety-critical environments. In these environments the exploitation of security vulnerabilities may result in major damages in the services infrastructures, financial or reputation losses to the organizations involved, and other catastrophic consequences for the users and the environment. Web services frameworks are the basis for developers to create and deploy web services, and must provide a robust ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>5</Quantity><Citation><Title>Assessing the security of web service frameworks against Denial of Service attacks.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Characterizing the performance of web service frameworks under security attacks.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Entwurf einer Methodik zum Testen der Sicherheit von Web-Service-basierten Systemen.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A new approach towards DoS penetration testing on web services.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>WSFAggressor: an extensible web service framework attacking tool.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>A Composed Approach for Automatic Classification of Web Services Robustness</Title><Authors>Rui Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2011/7/4</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Testing Web Services (WS) for robustness is a lengthy and arduous process. After testing a set of services, there is typically a very large quantity and variety of test results to be analyzed, which poses a challenge to the developer that has to manually process all results and identify the outputs that indicate the presence of bugs in the code. Previous research indicates that well-known automatic classification algorithms can be used to automate this step. However, the applicability of such algorithms is also limited, as they are frequently ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>2</Quantity><Citation><Title>Web Service classification using Multi-Layer Perceptron optimized with Tabu search.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in Service-centric System Testing.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>WSRTesting: Hands-on Solution to Improve Web Services Robustness Testing</Title><Authors>G Carrozza, A Napolitano, N Laranjeiro, M Viera</Authors><Publication_date>2011/4/25</Publication_date><Description>Abstract-Web services are widely used as software components that must provide a robust interface to client applications. Robustness testing is an approach particularly suitable for detecting robustness issues in web services. In fact, several research works have been conducted in the past leading to the proposal of different robustness testing techniques for such environments. However, although of utmost importance, most techniques do not consider the needs of complex systems and services as the ones being developed by the ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>1</Quantity><Citation><Title>Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in Service-centric System Testing.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>A Learning-Based Approach to Secure Web Services from SQL/XPath Injection Attacks</Title><Authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</Authors><Publication_date>2010/12/13</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Business critical applications are increasingly being deployed as web services that access database systems, and must provide secure operations to its clients. Although the open web environment emphasizes the need for security, several studies show that web services are still being deployed with command injection vulnerabilities. This paper proposes a learning-based approach to secure web services against SQL and XPath Injection attacks. Our approach is able to transparently learn valid request patterns ( ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>2</Quantity><Citation><Title>Aegis: Um Modelo de Proteção à Dados Sensíveis em Ambientes Client-side.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Attacks on Web Services Need to Secure XML on Web.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Applying Text Classification Algorithms in Web Services Robustness Testing</Title><Authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Rui Oliveira, Marco Vieira</Authors><Publication_date>2010/10/31</Publication_date><Description>Abstract—Testing web services for robustness is an effective way of disclosing software bugs. However, when executing robustness tests, a very large amount of service responses has to be manually classified to distinguish regular responses from responses that indicate robustness problems. Besides requiring a large amount of time and effort, this complex classification process can easily lead to errors resulting from the human intervention in such a laborious task. Text classification algorithms have been applied successfully in many ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>11</Quantity><Citation><Title>Data mining algorithms for Web-services classification.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A technique for deploying robust web services.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in Service-centric System Testing.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Robustness Evaluation of Software Systems through Fault Injection.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A systematic review of software robustness.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Testing and verification in service‐oriented architecture: a survey.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Web Classification Algorithm Using Support Vector Machine and Particle Swarm Optimization.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Specification-guided golden run for analysis of robustness testing results.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A robustness testing approach for SOAP Web services.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Locality Sensitive Hashing Based Service Classification.</Title><Date>2011</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A Composed Approach for Automatic Classification of Web Services Robustness.</Title><Date>2011</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication><Publication><Title>Effective Detection of SQL/XPath Injection Vulnerabilities in Web Services</Title><Authors>Nuno Antunes, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</Authors><Publication_date>2009/9/21</Publication_date><Description>Abstract This paper proposes a new automatic approach for the detection of SQL Injection and XPath Injection vulnerabilities, two of the most common and most critical types of vulnerabilities in web services. Although there are tools that allow testing web applications against security vulnerabilities, previous research shows that the effectiveness of those tools in web services environments is very poor. In our approach a representative workload is used to exercise the web service and a large set of SQL/XPath Injection attacks are ...</Description><Citations><Quantity>19</Quantity><Citation><Title>Assessing and Comparing Vulnerability Detection Tools for Web Services: Benchmarking Approach and Examples.</Title><Date>2015</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Characterization of attacks collected from the deployment of Web service honeypot.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Automated testing for SQL injection vulnerabilities: an input mutation approach.</Title><Date>2014</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>A Dynamic SQL injection vulnerability test case generation model based on the multiple phases detection approach.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Runtime Detection and Prevention for Structure Query Language Injection Attacks.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Security Testing in SOAs: Techniques and Tools.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Attacks on Web Services Need to Secure XML on Web.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Soa-scanner: An integrated tool to detect vulnerabilities in service-based infrastructures.</Title><Date>2013</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>CIVD: detection of command injection vulnerabilities in web services through aspect–oriented programming.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Model-based system architecture for preventing XPath injection in database-centric web services environment.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>WSFAggressor: an extensible web service framework attacking tool.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Evaluating and improving penetration testing in web services.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Attack model based penetration test for SQL injection vulnerability.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Experimental evaluation of web service frameworks in the presence of security attacks.</Title><Date>2012</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>XIVD: Runtime Detection of XPath Injection Vulnerabilities in XML Databases through Aspect Oriented Programming.</Title><Date>2011</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Comparison of penetration testing tools for web applications.</Title><Date>2011</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Enhancing penetration testing with attack signatures and interface monitoring for the detection of injection vulnerabilities in web services.</Title><Date>2011</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Security Standards Perspective to Fortify Web Database Applications From Code Injection Attacks.</Title><Date>2010</Date></Citation><Citation><Title>Benchmarking vulnerability detection tools for web services.</Title><Date>2010</Date></Citation></Citations></Publication></Publications></Researcher>